Guide to the Mooresville Mills Records, 1893-1962 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Mooresville Mills records 1893-1962 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Mooresville Mills
20.4 linear feet Extent: 15,290 Items
Manufacturer of cotton, wool, and synthetic fabrics, originally located in Mooresville, NC. Correspondence, minutes of meetings of stockholders and of directors, audit reports, financial statements, stock records, and general and subsidiary account books of a Mooresville, N.C., manufacturer of cotton, wool, and synthetic fabrics, draperies, upholstery, toweling, and wearing apparel, which was absorbed by Burlington Industries in 1955.
RL.00935
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Mooresville Mills Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1966.
Collection Overview
Records of a firm established in 1893 as Mooresville Cotton Mills by J. E. Sherrill and others, and later becoming a manufacturer of cotton, wool, and synthetic fabrics, draperies, upholstery, toweling, and clothing. The firm was absorbed by Burlington Industries in 1955. Included is a "historical file" of printed and typed articles; selected documents, 1914-1935, containing financial data; and photographs of employees, offices, and aerial photographs of the plant. There are also some legal documents relating to the firm's charter, receivership, and bylaws.
There are extensive minutes, 1893-1955, 3 vols., of meetings of stockholders and the board of directors; minutes, 1936-1951, of the executive committee of the board of directors; audit reports, 1921-1954; and financial statements, 1932-1933, 1937-1955. Stock records include common stock ledgers, 1893-1923, 5 vols.; a preferred stock ledger, 1917-1923; stock lists and miscellaneous records, 1897-1955; preferred stock certificates, 1917-1942; common stock certificates, 1893-1955; bonds for lost certificates, 1946-1955; broadsides for the issuance of preferred stock, 1923, and for a renewal, 1926. Appraisals of the corporation are dated 1935, 1946, and 1948. Account books include a journal and ledger, 1914-1916; cashbooks, 1905-1909, 2 vols.; cash journals, 1912-1913, 1921-1926, 3 vols.; check and deposit registers, 1948-1954, 3 vols.; cloth and towel inventories, 1936-1942, 1948-1949, 9 vols.; and a cost ledger, 1954. Unbound accounting records include inventories, 1933-1939, 1960-1962; local, state, and federal tax records, 1893-1956; and construction contracts and records, 1958-1960. There is also fragmentary correspondence, 1952-1955, for the towel division, the decorative fabrics division, the apparel fabrics division, and for William J. Fullerton who held various offices principally in merchandising and sales. For online images of the mill complex and its related mill village, see this website sponsored by the mill village association: Mooresville Mill slideshow.
Subject Headings
Burlington Industries, Inc.--History; Textile industry -- North Carolina; Industries -- North Carolina
Contents of Collection
- Financial Papers Series, 1893-1960, (42 boxes)
  - Audit Reports and Financial Papers, 1921-1935 June (Box 1)
  - Stock Records, 1897-1955 (Box 2)
  - Stock Ledgers, 1893-1923 (Box 2)
  - Stock Holders and Board of Directors Meetings
    - Appraisals, 1935, 1946, 1948 (Box 3)
    - Legal and Financial Papers (Box 4)
  - Audit Reports and Financial Papers
    - 1941 Sept.-1949 Apr. (Box 5)
    - 1949 Apr.-1954 Oct. (Box 6)
    - 1935 July-1941 June (Box 7)
  - Taxation and Employment Records, 1893-1956 (Box 8)
  - Common Stock Certificates
    - #2151-2350 (Box 26)
    - #1-401 (Box 30)
  - Preferred Stock Certificates
    - #402-602, 1923-1925 (Box 31)
    - #1-400, 1923-1925 (Box 32)
    - #401-600, 1925-1929 (Box 33)
  - Common Stock Certificates
    - #1-303, 1893-1903 (Box 34)
    - #304-654, 1903-1917 (Box 35)
    - #655-954, 1917-1920 (Box 36)
    - #955-1250, 1920-1922 (Box 37)
    - #1251-1550, 1922-1923 (Box 38)
    - #1551-1950, 1923-1924 (Box 39)
    - #1951-2150, 1924-1925 (Box 40)
    - #1-500, 1945-1946 (Box 41)
    - #501-1000, 1946 (Box 42)
    - #1001-1500, 1946 (Box 43)
  - Common Stock Certificates (fractional shares)
    - #505-1004, 1943-1946 (Box 44)
  - Bonds for Lost Certificates, 1946-1955 (Box 45)
  - Construction Contracts and Records, 1958-1960 (Box 45-46)
  - Common Stock Certificates
    - #1501-2000, 1946-1947 (Box 48)
    - #2001-2500, 1947-1948 (Box 49)
    - #2501-3000, 1948-1949 (Box 50)
    - #3001-3500, 1949 (Box 51)
    - #3501-4000, 1949-1950 (Box 52)
    - #4001-4500, 1950 (Box 53)
    - #4501-5000, 1950-1951 (Box 54)
    - #5001-5500, 1951-1952 (Box 55)
    - #5501-6000, 1952 (Box 56)
    - #6001-6500, 1952 (Box 57)
    - #6501-7000, 1952 (Box 58)
    - #7001-7500, 1952-1954 (Box 59)
    - #7501-8000, 1954-1955 (Box 60)
    - #8001-8750 (Box 61)
  - Common Stock Certificates (fractional shares)
    - #1-504, 1933-1943 (Box 62)
  - Taxation and Employment Records, 1893-1956 (Box 72A-B)
- Correspondence Series, (15 boxes)
  - Towel Division, NYC Office
    - A-Barklay (Box 9)
    - Bids-C (Box 10)
    - Carnes-G (Box 11)
    - Grant-Kuhn (Box 12)
    - K-Mill (Box 13)
    - Mill (Box 14)
  - Dec. Fabrics Division, NYC Office, Customer Correspondence
    - A-Co (Box 15)
    - Cr-Ez (Box 16)
    - Fa-Ho (Box 17)
    - Ho-Kr (Box 18)
    - Kr-Z (Box 19)
  - Apparel Division Correspondence
    - A-Bull (Box 19)
    - Bun-Form (Box 20)
    - Fore-Mack (Box 21)
    - Man-R (Box 22)
    - S-Z (Box 23)
- William J. Fullerton Files Series, 1953-1955, (6 boxes)
  - A-Atl (Box 23)
  - Bal-Ex (Box 24)
  - F-Fal (Box 25)
  - Ful-Los (Box 27)
  - List-Rad (Box 28)
  - Rad-Underwood (Box 29)
- Inventories Series, 1933-1962, (10 boxes)
  - Inventories
    - 1933-1934 (Box 47)
    - 1935-1936 (Box 63)
    - 1937 (Box 64)
    - 1938 (Box 65)
    - 1939 (Box 66)
  - Inventories, supplies, etc.
    - 1960 Jan.-Aug. (Box 67)
    - 1960 Oct.-Dec. (Box 68)
    - 1961 Jan.-July (Box 69)
    - 1961 Sept.-July (Box 70)
    - 1962 Mar. (Box 71)
- Oversize Material
  - Old and New Office Pictures, black and white photographs, undated (Box Sec. A OV5)